<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HTML Basics on Frontend Web Development</title>
    <link>/01-html-basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTML Basics on Frontend Web Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 12:37:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/01-html-basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectives</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/objectives/</guid>
      <description> Understand how web pages are structured
 Introduce some of the most frequently used html tags
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/agenda/</guid>
      <description> HTML Structure
 Overview of basic HTML Tags
 Code Along (GA Press Release)
 Lab (Cookie Recipe)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Structure</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/html-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/html-structure/</guid>
      <description>Front page of a newspaper
 Which elements stand out and why?
 What would happen if every word was the same size font?
 Structure helps readers better understand the stories written in the newspaper
  Word document
HTML document
 The above all have something in common - they are all documents
 The same principles that apply to newspapers and documents also apply to html pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Tag Anatomy</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/html-tag-anatomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/html-tag-anatomy/</guid>
      <description>What is a Tag?  Tags act like containers, they tell the browser what type of information lies between (aka the content) the opening and closing tag
 Opening Tag
 comprised of character(s) surrounded by less than and equal than signs (brackets) characters within the brackets indicates the tags purpose  Closing Tag
 Same as opening tag except closing tag contains a forward slash which informs browser that element has ended   Terms “tags” and “elements” are often used interchangeably</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Attributes</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/html-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/html-attributes/</guid>
      <description>What is an HTML Attribute?  Attributes provide additional information about the contents of the an element.
 They are placed in the opening tag
 They have two parts: name, value
  Attribute Structure  Attribute Name
 Indicates what kind of extra information you are supplying to the browser about the content in the element characters within the brackets indicates the tags purpose  Attribute Value</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag Overview</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/tag-overview/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
 Represents the root (top-level element) of an HTML document, so it is also referred to as the root element
 All other elements must be descendants of this element.
  &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
 Everything inside the body tag is shown inside the browser window  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
 Contains information about the page (vs shown on the pages
 Title and Links to other files are usually specified in the head element</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty Elements</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/empty-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/empty-elements/</guid>
      <description>What are Empty Elements?  Empty elements are elements that do not have a closing tag  &amp;lt;!-- p tags are NOT empty elements because they have a closing tag (&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;quot;) --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; I am not an empty element &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- img tags are considered empty elements because they DO NOT have a closing tag --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;images/team_hands&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;a group of people touching hands in a star formation&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;teamwork is awesome&amp;quot;&amp;gt;   Empty elements cannot contain child elements (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Along</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/code-along/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/code-along/</guid>
      <description> Code Along: GA Press Release  As a class, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through using html to build out an html version of a press release
 Using Sublime, open the folder called ga_press_release (found within the starter_code) folder
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab</title>
      <link>/01-html-basics/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-html-basics/lab/</guid>
      <description> Lab: Cookie Recipe  Work individually or in teams to create an html version of a Cookie recipe depicted in the images below
 Using Sublime, open the folder called cookie_recipe files for this exercise can be found in your starter_code
 Tips
 Focus on the content first, then the image then the CSS There will be some items that you will need to look up, CSS is one of them (don&amp;rsquo;t worry we will be going over this in the next class, but part of being a developer is being able to google your way to solutions)   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>